Finding Aid for George William Cushing papers and sound recordings, 1942-1955
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- In Our Opinion: recordings of programs, 7 in. reel-to-reel tapes; 7 1/2 ips
  - 1947
    - October 12, 1947 "Desperate Situation in Europe" (Box 6)
      (Guests: George Romney. (Bad surface))
    - October 19, 1947 "Youth Festival at Prague" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Eleanor Roberts, Harris Wofford, Jr.)
      (typescript of program in box 1)
    - October 26, 1947 "Situation in Europe" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Eugene C. Pulliam, Mrs. Nina Pulliam)
    - November 2, 1947 "Negro and Communism" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Ulysses W. Boykin, Edward W. Swan, Andrew J. Smith, Fred A. Allen, L. C. Blount)
    - November 3, 1947 Senator Arthur Vandenberg (Box 6)
    - November 11, 1947 Senator Arthur Vandenberg (Box 6)
    - November 30, 1947 "American Education in Far East" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Lowell Thomas, President Bayard Dodge)
    - December 21, 1947 "Uncle Sam in the role of Santa Claus" (foreign aid) (Box 6)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson and Representative Frank B. Keefe)
    - December 28, 1947 "Disabled War Veterans Employment Problems" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Frank X. Martel, Howard K. Kelley, Robert A. Oliver)
  - 1948
    - January 18, 1948 "Michigan Problems as Seen from Arizona" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Governor Kim Sigler)
    - January 25, 1948 "Present Situation in Greece" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Dr. Ernest W. Riggs)
    - February 8, 1948 "The Kon-Tiki Raft Expedition" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Thor Heyerdahl)
    - February 15, 1948 "Michigan Highway Plans" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Thomas H. MacDonald, J. P. Buckley, Don B. Smith)
    - February 22, 1948 "American Legion Discusses 'Americanism.'" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Arthur Clark, Herman Luhrs, Victor Galloway, Floyd Haight, William Malloy, Leo Navarre, Hugh H. Neale, Wilbur Brucker, Joseph Kornfedder, Walter Scott)
    - February 29, 1948 or February 28, 1948 "Britain" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Colonel James Riley Holt Hutchinson)
    - March 7, 1948 "Cruises in the Persian Gulf, etc" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Commander Alan Villiers, George Pierrot)
    - March 14, 1948 "Communist Activities in the Schools" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Governor Kim Sigler, President Alexander G. Ruthven, President David D. Henry, President John A. Hannah)
    - March 21, 1948 "Inroads Made by Communism into American Life and Business" (Box 6)
      (Guests: William Umstaddt, Dr. Maurice Lieber, Harold S. Vincent, Don S. Cordray)
    - April 11, 1948 "Detroit Fire Department" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Chief Ninnian C. Higby, Richard F. Reaume, Jr., Commissioner Paxton Mendelsohn, Commissioner J. L. Mahon, Chief Kendall, (Members of Fire Dept.: Orel, Beer, Galbraith, Morske, Holdhouse, St. John, Vincent), T. Curtis McKenzie)
    - April 25, 1948 "Conditions in France" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Edward Cruskin, David Schonbrun, Jeffery Parsons (from Paris), Patrick Walberg, Pierre Crenesse)
    - May 9, 1948 "Problems Today that Worry Mothers" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Mrs. LeRoy E. Cowles, Mrs. Byron J. Chambers, Mrs. John C. Henderson, Mrs. Ulysses Boykin)
    - May 16, 1948 "Situation in Europe Today" (Box 6)
      (Guests: W. H. Lawrence (Foreign Correspondent, NY Times))
    - May 23, 1948 "Communism in Schools" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Russell H. Wilson (Supt. Alpena Public Sch.), Otto W. Haisley (Supt. Ann Arbor Pub. Sch.), Herman L. Shibler (Supt. Highland Park Sch.), George T. Cantrick (Supt. Monroe Public Schools))
    - June 6, 1948 "Michigan State College Students" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Dr. John A. Hannah (Pres. MSC), Tom King (Director Alumni Relations), Miss Ruth Meinke (Detroit), Miss Fay Flakely (Gibraltar), Rollie Young (Lansing), Don Borgeson (Chicago, IL), Elliott Fritz (Schenectady, NY))
    - June 13, 1948 "Delegates from Sweden" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Mr. Allan Kastrup (GM Swedish News Exchange), Mr. Kridman (Swedish Adult Educational), Mr. Kugelberg (Pres. Swedish Employers Confederation))
    - September 29, 1948 "Conditions in Japan" (Box 6)
      (Guests: Bunshiro Suzuki (Japanese editor of Reader's Digest in Japan))
    - October 3, 1948-"Odd Jobs, Inc" (Box 7)
      (Guests: John Gilmore, Jim Wood, Melvin Earegood, Elvin Wood, Mrs. Al Rones)
    - October 5, 1948 Miscellaneous topics (Box 7)
    - October 17, 1948 "Airport Developments" (Box 7)
      (Guests: James C. Buckley (Director-Airport Devel. NY Port Authority), Col. J. Victor Dallen (Pres. Airport Oprs' Council Philadelphia), Ken Smith (Capitol Airlines), Jack Tompkins (American Airlines), Eugene Fryhoff (Dir. Detroit Metropolitan Aviation Authority))
    - October 24, 1948 "Conditions in Korea" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Dr. Frank L. Eversull (Educator, Author, Lecturer))
    - October 31, 1948 "Everyday Religion" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Dr. Don Tullis, Worth Kramer)
    - November 7, 1948 "Adventures of a Sea Raider" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Count Felix von Luckner)
    - November 14, 1948 "Reasons Behind the Negro Vote" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Rev. Theodore S. Boone (Rep. Co-ord. Com of Mich.), Rev. Robert L. Bradby, Jr. (National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Pres.), Ulysses W. Boykin (Editor Detroit Tribune), Victor Hicks (Wayne County Demo Com.))
    - November 21, 1948 "Defense Plans for Michigan" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Donald S. Leonard (Comm. Mich. State Police), John Huss (Director, Mich. Municipal League), John Witherspoon (Asst. Corp Counsel Detroit))
    - November 28, 1948 "Conditions In Europe As Seen From A Trailer" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr. (Journalist & Lecturer))
    - December 5, 1948 "North American Indians" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Fred Ettawagshik, Norman I. Ewing, Dr. Thomas J. Jameson, Louis A. Morago)
    - December 12, 1948 "Baby Treatment" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Dr. Howard C. Walser, Dr. John C. Montgomery, Dr. Donald J. Barnes, Dr. James Wilson)
    - December 19, 1948 "Security" (Unification of The United States Armed Services) (Box 7)
      (Guests: S.L.A. Marshall)
  - 1949
    - January 5, 1949 "Exchange Students Back From Abroad" (Box 7)
      (Guests: William Miller (U of M), Fred Keydel (Yale), Patricia Lytle (Wayne), Harvey Wiseberg (U of M), Sam Schwartz (Wayne))
    - January 9, 1949 "British Embassy Answers Vanderbilt" (Box 7)
      (Guests: D.F.H. Brickell, (British Consulate General), A.N. Duckham (Agricultural Attache to Embassy, Wash. DC))
    - January 30, 1949 "China Today" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Professor Russell H. Fifield (U of M), Russell Barnes (Det. News Foreign Corres.))
    - February 20, 1949 "Alcoholism" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Hon. Robert W. Kenny (formerly Atty-Gen of Calif.), Judge Lewis Drucker (Judge Municipal Court-Cleveland), James Montante (Pres. Detroit Chapter -- Nat'l Lawyers Guild), Mr. X (A Member of Alcoholics Anonymous))
    - March 6, 1949 "Indonesia" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Sayid A. Almassawa (S. Sumatra), Dr. Amry Vandenbosch (U. of Kentucky), Russell Barnes (Detroit News), Willard C. Wichers (Holland, Mich.))
    - March 13, 1949 "Ocean Sailing" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Commander Alan Villiers)
    - March 20, 1949 "Child Welfare" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Mrs. Dermot Morrah (British Magistrate), Miss Evangeline Schibley (Det. Council Social Agencies))
    - April 3, 1949 "Candidates for School Board" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Louise C. Grace, Patrick V. McNamara, Frank A. Gorman, James H. Lincoln, Jane Lovejoy, Richard A. MacRae)
    - April 17, 1949 "Conditions in Far East (Easter)" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Dr. Frederick H. Olert)
    - April 24, 1949 "What Future for DSR?" (Detroit Street Railway) (Box 7)
      (Guests: Leo J. Nowicki (Gen. Mgr., DSR), Del Smith (Councilman), Louis Miriani (Councilman))
    - May 1, 1949 "Nationalists & Communists at Nanking" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Harold K. Milks (AP Correspondent from China))
    - May 8, 1949 "International Institute Members Discuss America" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Mrs. Shumi Wickel (Japan), Mrs. Joseph Fasi (Malta), Mrs. Glen R. Magary (France), Mrs. James Williamson (England), Miss Madeline Felkl (Hungary), Mrs. Janina K. Hoski (Poland), Miss Wilma Oraham (Persia), Miss Lucette Winnie (Belgium), Miss Amelia Hakim (Bagdad, Iraq), Miss Monique Leutwyler (Switzerland), Miss Alice L. Sickels (Ex. Dir. Int'l Inst.))
      (Interview with ten women from foreign countries who have come to US to make their home)
    - May 22, 1949 "Boys Republic" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Richard Burke (Field Director), Pat Lovejoy (Pres. Board of Directors), Charles Henry (Exe. Director), Marvin Harrison (Citizen & Pres. Boys Rep.), Anthony Rish (Citizen & Judge), C. F. Ramsey (Supt. Mich. Children's Inst. AA))
    - May 28, 1949, Senator Arthur Vandenberg, 2 tapes (Box 7)
    - June 12, 1949 "American International Trade Fair" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Mr. Willis Hall (Secretary Bd. Of Com.), Roy W. Gifford (Chairman World Affairs Bd. Of Com.), Richard Frost (Secretary World Affairs Bd. Of Com.), Dr. Jacques Kunstenaar (Washington Dept. Commerce), Dr. G. M. Franci (Italy), Dr. J. Milius (Netherlands))
    - October 16, 1949 "90 Years Progress in the Oil Industry" (Box 7)
      (Guests: P. J. Hoffmaster (Dir. of Mich. Dept. of Conservation), Kurt DeCousser (Chg. Of Prod. & Pipe Line -- Socony Vacuum), Stanley Frank (Shell Service Stat. Dealer, Ferndale), C. Z. Hardwick (Findlay, Ohio, V. P. of Ohio Oil Co.))
    - November 6, 1949 "Governor Murray Van Wagoner -- Bavaria" (condition in Germany) (Box 7)
      (Guests: Murray D. Van Wagoner (Former Military Gov. of Bavaria, etc.))
    - December 4, 1949 "Sir Andrew Murray and St. Andrew's Society of Detroit Members"
      (Guests: Sir Andrew Murray (Lord Provost of Edinburgh), James R. Allan (Pres. St. Andrew's Society of Detroit), Andrew Baird (Sheriff of Wayne), Martin Thompson (2nd Vice President St. Andrews), John Henry (oldest member of St. Andrew's), Harry Clisdale (Secy. Bd. Of Trustees), Frank R. S. Campsie (President-elect), Judge David C. Vokes, Wm. Urquhart (Master-at-Arms -- Past Pres. of St. Andrew's), Lt. Jos. W. Pont. (Detroit Police Dept.))
    - December 11, 1949 "Mental Health Program for Detroit and Michigan" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Dr. B. Benedict Glazer (Rabbi of Temple Beth El and Pres., Wayne County Chapter -- Michigan Society for Mental Hygiene))
    - December 18, 1949 "Report on World Conditions by Senator Ferguson" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson (Michigan's Senator))
    - December 25, 1949 "Christmas Day in Bastogne-1944" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Major Gen. Anthony C. McAuliffe (Chief Army Chemical Corps.), Colonel S.L.A. Marshall (Editorial Writer Detroit News), and Five Veterans Who Fought With General McAuliffe At Bastogne)
    - Undated (late 40's), "Pres. Truman's Request For A Loan To Greece To Stem Threat Of Communism In That Country" "Meet Your Congress" (Box 7)
      (Guests: Blair Moody (Moderator), Senators Taft (R-Ohio), Pepper (D-Fla.), Hatch (D-N.M.), Ferguson (R-Mich.))
      (partial recording-approx. first 17 minutes-surface very bad)
  - 1950
    - January 1, 1950-"United Foundation -- First-of-the-year Report" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Walter Laidlaw (Gen. Mgr. United Foundation), Dr. Ethel Calhoun (Sister Kenny Foundation), Jack Pardee (Former Patient of Sister Kenny Foundation), Mrs. Clare Kidder (Epileptic Clinic), Mrs. Nelson McCormack (League for the Handicapped), Mr. Ray Wunschel (League for the Handicapped), Brother Flavian (St. Joseph Home for Boys), Four Boys from the St. Joseph Home for Boys)
    - January 8, 1950 "2nd Report on World Conditions-Sen. Ferguson" (Box 8)
      (Introduction missing from discs-bad surface)
    - January 15, 1950 "Bridge Across Straits of Mackinac"
      (Guests: Mr. Fred M. Alger, Jr. (Secretary of State), Mr. John McCarthy (Chairman of the State Public Service Commission and Chairman of the Inter-Peninsula Communications Commission), Mr. W. S. Woodfill (Chairman of the Mackinac Bridge Citizen's Committee), Professor Kenneth K. Landes (Chairman of the Department of Geology, University of Michigan))
    - February 26, 1950 "Bishop Joseph Kiwanuka's Discussion on Africa" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Bishop Joseph Kiwanuka (Uganda, Central East Africa), Right Reverend Monsignor Leo DeBarry (Dir. of Missionary Activities in Detroit Archdiocese), Reverend P. O. L'Heureux (Bishop's Secretary, also of White Fathers of Africa))
    - April 2, 1950 "Industrial Mobilization Problems in Detroit" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Col. Walter Godard (U.S. Air Force), Col. Melvin G. Brown (U.S. Marine Corp), Col. George A. Harvey (U.S. Army), Lt. Col. Markus R. King (U.S. Air Force), Commander Charles E. Pond (U. S. Navy), Dale McIntyre (Assisting Mr. Cushing).)
      (bad surface)
    - May 14, 1950 "Police Chiefs" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Capt. Harold Mulbar (Michigan State Police), Albert Muller (Chief Rural Traffic Police of Stuttgart, Germany), Professor Arthur F. Brandstatter (Head of Mich. State's Police Administration Dept)
      (The first half of the original was bad)
    - May 21, 1950 "Traffic Courts" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Judge Geo. T. Murphy (Detroit Traffic Judge), Judge John D. Watts (Detroit Traffic Judge), Judge Paul Younger (Lansing-Head of the Municipal Judges Ass. of Mich.), Judge Henry Hart (Midland), Emmet Robinson (Justice of the Peace from Bridgeport, Mich.))
    - May 28, 1950 "Mr. Angus Ward" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Mr. Angus Ward, Dale McIntyre)
      (Ward was held prisoner by the Chinese)
    - July 2, 1950 "Korea-Rebroadcast of Dr. Eversull, 10/24/48" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Dr. Eversull)
    - July 23, 1950 "Korean Situation" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Col. S.L.A. Marshall, Maj. Marshall Andrews, Joseph Hainline)
    - October 1, 1950 "To Live With The Atom" (regarding the Phoenix Memorial Project) (Box 8)
      (Guests: Homer Ferguson (Senator from Michigan), Morse Salisbury (Atomic Energy Commission), Dr. Marshall E. Dimock (Professor of Political Science))
      (The surface of the disc was poor)
    - October 22, 1950 "Conditions in India" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Dr. Arthur T. Mosher, Rev. John Bathgate (Presbytery of Detroit))
    - October 29, 1950 "Interview about Pakistan" (Box 8)
      (Guests: His Excellency, Mirza Abol Hassan Ispahani (First Ambassador of Pakistan))
    - November 5, 1950 "Proposal No. 2" (mental health care). (Box 8)
      (Guests: Ray R. Eppert (V.P. Burroughs Adding Machine Co.), Hon. Judge Arthur E. Moore (Probate Court, Oakland County), Dr. Harry E. August (Commissioner of the Michigan Department of Mental Health), Mr. Harold G. Webster (Executive Director of the Michigan Society for Mental Hygiene).)
  - 1951
    - January 21, 1951 "Grandfather Dr. Samuel A. Mudd assistance to John Wilkes Booth" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Colonel Richard D. Mudd (Chief Surgeon of the 105h Air Force, Selfridge Field Air Force Base))
    - January 28, 1951 "Need for an Atlantic Union" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Mrs. Stellanova Osborn (Widow of the late Chase S. Osborn))
      (The surface of the disc was very poor)
    - March 4, 1951 "Korea During Red Invasion" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Mr. and Mrs. Milton C. Towner (Birmingham, Michigan) (Mrs. Milton C. Towner was secretary to Syngman Rhee))
    - June 3, 1951 "Some Neglected Aspects of Communism" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Rt. Rev. Richard S. Emrich (Bishop of the Protestant Episcopal Diocese of Michigan))
    - July 8, 1951 "Philippines" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Felino Neri (Manila), Mr. Norman Hill)
    - September 16, 1951 "Edward Murrow's Comments Two-way Interview" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Edward R. Murrow)
    - September 23, 1951 "Foreign Student's Impressions of United States" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Andrew Sinclair (Sydney, Australia), Miss Sharda Verma (Lucknow, India), Finn Monies (Copenhagen, Denmark), Takashi Watanobe (Tokyo, Japan), Jack Daniels (N.A.M.))
    - September 30, 1951 "China" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Father Leon Sullivan (Fr. Sullivan was imprisoned and deported by Communist China))
    - October 21, 1951 "Report on World Trip"
      (Guests: Bishop Emrich)
    - October 28, 1951 "Soroptimist Club" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Miss Martha Servis (Philadelphia), Miss Helen Foche (Cleveland), Professor Nuzhet Gokdogan (Turkey), Miss Elizabeth Douvan (Ann Arbor), Mrs. Ella W. Gitteau (Akron))
    - November 18, 1951 "Africa" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Mr. Balamu J. Mukasa (Prime Minister of Uganda))
    - December 2, 1951 "Confusion in Korea" (Box 8)
      (Guests: General S.L.A. Marshall (Detroit News), Royce Howes (Detroit Free Press))
  - 1952
    - February 17, 1952 "Athletics" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Dr. John Hannah (President of Mich. State College))
    - March 16, 1952 "Malaya" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Miss Rhona Connery)
    - April 6, 1952 "Detroit Flood Control" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Miss Mae Jordan (American Red Cross), Mr. Samuel B. Morris (General Manager and Chief Engineer of Dept. of Water and Power for City of Los Angeles))
    - June 22, 1952 "Communism" (Russian domination of Poland). (Box 8)
      (Guests: Dr. Tadeusz Bielecki (Chairman of Polish National Democratic Party), Mr. Benjamin C. Stanczyk (Assistant Prosecuting Attorney of Wayne County))
    - July 6, 1952 "Republican National Convention" (Box 8)
      (Guests: D. Hale Brake (State Treasurer of Michigan), Congressman John Bennett (12th District), Collin Smith (Former State Senator), Ben Burdick (Chairman of 15th Congressional District), Joe Hainline)
    - July 20, 1952 "Democratic Convention" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Senator Edwin Johnson (Colorado))
    - August 24, 1952 "Grosse Isle" (Box 8)
      (Guests: Captain Eddie R. Sanders (Commanding Officer of Grosse Isle), Lt. William Luddy (Command Liaison Officer))
    - August 26, 1952 Senator Arthur Vandenberg (Box 8)
    - October 19, 1952 "Mott Foundation Program" (Flint Public School System) (Box 8)
      (Guests: Mr. C.S. Mott (Leading Citizen and Supporter of Community School Idea), Mr. Frank Manley (Director of Mott Foundation), Mrs. Elizabeth Smith (Principal of Freeman School), Bill Minardo (Director of School Activities), Mr. and Mrs. Jim Gleason, Mr. and Mrs. Jack Hudson, Miss Ola Miller, Harold Bacon, Mary Nell Walker, Judy Anderson, Becky Feleski, Stephanie Rose, Mr. and Mrs. Don Steibel, Mr. and Mrs. Douglas Jenkins, Jim Rush, Helen Beacon, Ron Gamble, Dale McIntyre)
    - November 2, 1952-"Communism in Malaya" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Sir Gerald Templar (High Commissioner of Malaya), Right Honorable Malcolm MacDonald (Commissioner), General for Southeast Asia, Garage Owner and Planter's Wife)
    - November 9, 1952 "Far East" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Father John E. Duffy (National Chaplain of the American Legion))
    - November 23, 1951 "This I Believe" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Edward R. Murrow (CBS), Edward P. Morgan (CBS), Leonard P. Simmons, Virginia Sale, Justice William O. Douglas)
    - December 14, 1952 "China" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Father Mark Tennien (Maryknoll Order))
    - December 28, 1952 "Africa"
      (Guests: Mr. Lou Lorentz (Moorman Travel Service))
  - 1953
    - January 18, 1953 "University of Detroit" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Arthur Godfrey, Father Celestin J. Steiner, S.J.)
    - March 8, 1953 "Report from Uganda" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Mr. Balamu J. Mukasa)
    - March 29, 1953 "Life in America" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Mr. and Mrs. Gyan Kohli (India), Michael Koh (Singapore), Der-Shyang Ling (Singapore))
    - April 5, 1953 "Malaya" (Box 9)
    - May 17, 1953 "India and Iceland" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Mr. Lalchand Hirachand (Bombay, India), Mr. V. M. Meswani (Bombay, India), Mr. Dadi Hjorvar (Iceland))
    - May 31, 1953 "Hot Rods and Sport Cars" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Dr. Walton E. Cole (Pastor, First Congregational Church, Detroit), James T. Moore (Nash Motors), Alan Symond (Henry Ford Museum))
    - June 14, 1953 "Barber Shop Quartets" (Box 9)
      (Guests: John Z. Means (International President), O. C. Cash (Founder), Carroll Adams (International Secretary), The Schmidt Brothers (1951 Champions, 4 members), the Four Teens (1952 Winners, and their leader), The Vikings (1953 Winners, 4 members), Bud Arkberg)
    - June 26, 1953 "50th Anniversary Detroit Board of Commerce" Address by Roger Keys
    - June 28, 1953 "Korea" (Box 9)
      (Guests: General S.L.A. Marshall)
    - July 5, 1953 (1), "Jackson Prison" (Box 9)
      (Guests: William Bannan (Warden), Edward L. Colbert (Director of Classification), Arthur Miller (Counselor), The following inmates: Conrad Payne (Editor, The Spectator), Enis Gilliam, Frank Siple, Floyd Hurl, Robert Hamilton, John Myers)
    - July 5, 1953 (2), "Jackson Prison" (Box 9)
    - August 9, 1953 "Classic Car Club" (Box 9)
      (Guests: James J. Nance (President, Packard Motor Car C.), Gordon Webber (New York, President of Classic Car Club), W. H. Graves (Vice President, Packard's), David Wilkie (Associated Press), Priestly Blake, Robert Turnquist, Joseph Sulley)
    - August 16, 1953 "Pakistan" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Mr. Mohammed Sulaiman Kakli)
    - August 23, 1953 "Ethiopia" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Francis A. Kornegay (Detroit Urban League), Syoum Gebregsizbher (U of M Student), Habt Sellassie Taffassa (Carlton College Student), Clyde D. Francis (Student at Allegheny College, Pa.))
    - September 27, 1953 "Brain Washing" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Edward Hunter (Author), Mr. Wilbert Marlett)
    - October 4, 1953 "Starr Commonwealth" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Mr. Floyd Starr (Founder and President of Starr Commonwealth), Honorable Howard Pyle (Governor of Arizona), Mrs. Ruth Bryan Rohde (Former Ambassador to Denmark))
    - October 11, 1953 "Germany" (Box 9)
    - November 15, 1953 "Lowell Thomas" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Lowell Thomas)
    - November 29, 1953 "Africa" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Dr. George H. T. Kimble (Twentieth Century Fund, New York), Mr. Nagaui Shuaibu (Nigerian Educational Director))
  - 1954
    - January 3, 1954 or January 4, 1954 "Wayne University" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Dr. Clarence Hilberry (President of Wayne University))
    - January 10, 1954 "Japan" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Kenji Kimura (Tokyo, Japan), Edward R. Murrow (CBS Reporter), Bob Pierpont (Japan))
    - January 17, 1954 "American Architecture" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Mr. Willem M. Dudok (Dutch Architect), Mr. Willard C. Wichers (Holland, Michigan), Mr. Willem Von Weiler (Netherlands Consul, Detroit))
    - January 24, 1954 "Crime Solving" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Mr. Raymond C. Schindler (Private Detective, NY))
    - January 31, 1954 "Japan" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Honorable Ronzo Sawada (Ambassador to the United Nations for Japan), Rt. Rev. Richard S. Emrich (Bishop of the Diocese of Michigan), Dr. Paul Rusch (Tokyo, Japan), Lt. Gen. C.H. Lee (Retired, York, Pa.))
    - February 7, 1954 "United Nations" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Dr. Archibald J. Carey, Jr. (United States Delegate to the United Nations))
    - February 14, 1954 "Mental Health" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Dr. Winfred Overholser (Superintendent of St. Elizabeth's Hospital), Dr. Jack R. Ewalt (Commissioner of Mental Health for State of Massachusetts))
    - February 21, 1954 "George Washington" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Mr. Kenneth Metcalf (Detroit Public Library))
    - February 28, 1954 "Rheumatic Fever" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Dr. Leon DeVel (Grand Rapids, Medical Coordinator of Rheumatic Fever Control, Michigan State Medical Society), Dr. John Bielawski (Detroit, Director of Michigan Heart Association), Dr. Manes S. Hecht (Detroit, Wayne County Rheumatic Fever Control Committee), Philip Butkovich (Victim of Rheumatic Fever))
    - March 7, 1954 "Motion Pictures" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Armand Denis (Photographer and Producer))
    - March 14, 1954 "Handling of Young Men" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Clarence "Biggie" Munn (Athletic Director of Michigan State College))
    - March 21, 1954 "France" (Box 9)